RESUME

Rachel Wanjiku P.O. Box 343-00232 Mobile: 0789170247

Email: wanjiku.rachel@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I am a self driven, fast and eager learner with great attention to detail. I enjoy working with technology be it in Technical Support or Creating Web based applications. I am in a constant process of learning new technologies to keep updated with current advances.

I aim to grow and learn and take every job opportunity as a learning experience and as I continue to grow my skills.

Skills

- Proficient in Frontend frameworks I.e Angularjs and Reactjs.
- Understanding of Javascript ES6
- Experience using HTML5 and CSS3 as well as Bootstrap
- Experience using Ubuntu/Linux and its applications.
- Experience with version control technologies such as GIT
- Experience and training in mySQL, Postgresql databases
- Experience with Ruby on Rails and Python using Flask.

•

Experience

Online work March 2022 to Present – Various remote work Platforms

- Reviewing all work submitted by taskers in audio, Image and video tasks.
- Reviewing training materials and giving feedback on areas that need improvement, omitted information and errors that could reduce quality of training.
- Participating on evaluation of new project tasks and instructions and providing feedback on what information would improve training.
- Testing of new tools implemented and providing feedback on their effectiveness in completing tasks.
- Working as a transcriber converting audio/video to text
- Working as a writer for clients on various research topics in different fields.

Bakery Manager/owner - Jan 2019 – March 2022 Self – Ruiru

- Controlled ordering of ingredients and packaging from suppliers and vendors to ensure supply and storage consistency.
- Took complete accountability of bakery display management activities to ensure all products were aesthetically placed in display boxes.
- Earned in-depth knowledge of all ingredients, mixing, bakery equipment, maintenance, icings and color coordination.
- Handled complete bakery functions, including menu pricing, calculating production costs, reducing wastes, increasing profit margin and recipe costing.
- Supervised and mentored employees in following proper procedures to produce and sell quality products.

BPO Executive

Sama Kenya – Data Annotation Agent – Jan 2016 - March 2018

- Worked on building training data for computer vision algorithms.
- Working together with supervisor and management to achieve client satisfaction.
- Reviewing work submitted to ensure there are no quality issues and giving feedback

•

Sama Kenya - Junior Software Developer Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

- Coded programs in diverse programming languages based on specific functionality requirements.
- Employed best practices in software development to complete high-quality applications in line with scheduled targets.
- Integrated design feedback to build and maintain user-centered software applications.
- Worked within Agile frameworks to consistently meet project timelines and deliverable objectives.
- Managed software development life-cycle, leveraging project management and leadership talents.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging and optimization.
- Collaborated with UI/UX personnel to integrate ease-of-use and accessibility considerations into developed software.
- Determined whether user needs could be incorporated into existing applications or required new development.

Computer Technician Intern

Jomo Kenyatta University of Technology November 2013 – February 2014

- Trained users in proper use and care of computers to reduce and eliminate potentially damaging errors.
- Researched and tested new hardware and software to keep current with technological developments.
- Checked PCs and laptops to troubleshoot, trace and resolve customer issues.
- Verified hardware and software of new office employee workstations.
- Added new hardware, software, security patches and other updates to improve functionality of computer systems.
- Removed viruses and unwanted software from desktop operating systems using logical and systematic processes.
- Installed conduit, connection boxes and devices to complete networks and tested pieces for functionality.
- Installed new office wiring, telephones and devices for employee use.
- Repaired or replaced malfunctioning electrical and mechanical components of equipment.

Customer Service Executive Orange/Telkom Jan – 2010 to August 2012

- Shared insights with management regarding member inquiries, concerns and complaints to improve products, operations and policies.
- Communicated with clients over phone, email and chat platforms.
- Conducted follow-up calls at customer locations.

- Validated data and resolved problems related to system-generated information.
- Communicated and followed up with prospective members via phone or email to process pending account applications.
- Exceeded requirements and deadlines when providing products and services to customers.
- Used up-selling and cross-selling techniques to provide solutions to customer issues.
- Resolved customer inquiries, complaints and issues and used problem solving techniques to provide solutions.
- Processed customer product orders in collaboration with third-party fulfillment vendor.
- Monitored and resolved product and service issues promptly.

Education

Bachelor of Science : Computer Science -3^{rd} year In progress - ODEL Presbyterian University Of East Africa - Nairobi

Certificate of training in MySQL and Oracle SQL Database Management Institute of Software Technologies – August 2014

Diploma in Business and Information Technology Presbyterian University Of East Africa – Graduated December 2015

High School Diploma : KCSE St. Francis High School – Thika

Referees

Peter Muthike, Senior Software Engineer, Mobile: 0713026413

Phillip Kamau
Department Of Computer Science (Head)
Presbyterian University of East Africa
P.O. BOX 387 – 00902, Thogoto Kikuyu
Mobile: 0724797528

Eric Miriti Mwenda Senior Software Engineer Sama Kenya

Mobile: 0729956363